Virginia Radley Papers
State University of New York at Oswego
- Newspaper Clippings, 1983 (Box-folder 2-4)
  Newspaper clippings and other published materials relating to Dr. Radley. "The Business Behind The School". Palladium-Times, January 11, 1983. "SUCO Faculty Weighs Strategies to Fight Cuts" by Mike Grogan. Post-Standard. February 11, 1983. "SUCO Faculty Talk of Saving Jobs" by Mike Grogan. The Post-Standard. February 3, 1983. "Budget Cuts Hitting Home" by Steve Yablonski. Palladium-Times. February 5, 1983. "SUNY College President Clarifies Stance on Budget, Position Cuts. Oswego County Messenger. February 11, 1983. "SUNY President Issues Call To Arms" by Joanne Berman. The Palladium-Times. February 11, 1983. "Radley Restates Plea for Autonomy on Local Campuses". Post-Standard, February 22, 1983. "Finance 101. College cuts spell $7 million loss to Oswego". Oswego Accent Plus. February 24, 1983. "SUCO's Radley to take five-month study leave" by Mike Grogan. Syracuse Herald American. April 10, 1983. "Women-only schools serve purpose: college heads" by Mark D. Frank. Syracuse Herald American. October 9, 1983. "Two College Presidents Champion Women's Schools" by Mark D. Frank. Buffalo Evening News. October 28, 1983.
- Newspaper Clippings, 1984 (Box-folder 2-5)
  Newspaper clippings and other published materials relating to Dr. Radley. "The Women Oswegonians Admire". Palladium-Times, January 11, 1984. "Horton Selects Radley For Committee". Palladium-Times, January 28, 1984. "Hike rent on Radley's on-campus home; College council member". Syracuse Herald Journal, February 16, 1984. "Former SUCO Presidents say Sheldon Beach Never Open to Public". Post Standard, March 7, 1984. "Oswego Releases Report on Plans for Sheldon Beach". Post Standard, March 9, 1984. "Council OKs Suing SUCO Over Beach Use". Post Standard, March 13, 1984. "Radley Wants Autonomy Over Budget" by Antone Clark. Palladium-Times. March 20, 1984. "Oswego's desires for a swimming hole splits town and gown. College estate or public beach?" Palladium-Times, March 25, 1984. "College Head Addresses 13 Honorees, Guests" by Natalie Pitzer. Union-Sun & April 9, 1984. "Cahill Sues SUCO Chief to Reopen Sheldon's Beach". Post Standard, August 29, 1984. "State Represents Radley in Sheldon Beach Suit". Post Standard, September 21, 1984. "Radley: Sheldon Hall Plan May be in Trouble". Post Standard, October 4, 1984. "Dr. Radley Presented With Service Award By Russell Sage". Palladium-Times, December 7, 1984.
- Newspaper Clippings, 1985 - 1988 (Box-folder 2-6)
  Newspaper clippings and other published materials relating to Dr. Radley. "Cahill's Beach Suit Dismissed". Pallaldium-Times, January 31, 1985. "Court: SUCO Can Ban Swimming at Sheldon Beach". Post Standard, February 1, 1985. "Dr. Radley Receives Research Grant". Palladium-Times. July 24, 1985. "Madame President Reigns at Oswego". Central New York Business Review, August 1985. "Radley is Named". Palladium-Times. January 15, 1986. "Coach Accuses Radley of Harassment" by Maggie Reed. Palladium-Times. March 7, 1986. "Radley Cites Three For Academic Excellence". Palladium-Times. April 26, 1986. "Wealth Matters, Radley Says To Students". Palladium-Times. May 16, 1986. "Radley Makes Recommendation To Appoint Moody As Dean". Palladium-Times. August 6, 1986. "Radley to Participate In Women's Conference". Palladium-Times. October 20, 1986. "Boronkay Appointed Associate Dean". Palladium-Times. November 19, 1986. "Radley Extends Hours For Guns". Palladium-Times. March 5, 1987. "Radley Sees A 'Grim, Awful' Budget". Palladium-Times. March 19, 1987. "SUNY's first woman president resumes teaching and research" by Julie Harrison Blissert. State University of New York focus on Women. March 1988. "If There's Something Unique Oswego offers.. ." Campus News. The Sage Alumnae Magazine. Volume 8. Includes article, "Virginia Radley Receives Crockett Award". Page 7.
- Newspaper Clippings, 1992 - 1993 (Box-folder 2-7)
  Newspaper clippings and other published materials relating to Dr. Radley. "Radley Named Scholar in Residence". Sage Times. January 29, 1993. "Woman educator made history with SUNY Oswego post". Post-Standard. March 13, 1992. (Formerly 1/9/194)
- Proposal for a Competency-Based Teacher Education Program, 1983 (Box-folder 2-8)
  Proposal for a Competency-Based Teacher Education Program leading to the Degree, Master of Science in Education, Major in Industrial Arts and Technology by State University of New York, College of Arts and Sciences at Oswego. 41 pages included appendix and supporting correpondence. (Formerly 1/9/194)
- Publications, 1984 - 1986 (Box-folder 2-9)
  The US Undergrad, Vol. 1, No. 1, Fall 1984. The Newsletter of the Undergraduate Alumni Association, SUNY Oswego. Front page article includes Perspective from President of College - Dr. Virginia Radley. 2 copies. 125th Commencement, Class of 1986.
- Memorandum of Understanding, April, 1980 (Box-folder 2-10)
  Memorandum of Understanding between The State Universty of New York, College of Environmental Science and Forestry and The State University of New York at Oswego signed by Dr. Virginia L. Radley and Edward E. Palmer. SUNY College of Environmental Science and Forestry and SUNY Oswego signed cooperative programming pact to increase inter-campus cooperation in research, public service and educational programs in the natural and environmental sciences. See folder 02-02 for newspaper photograph and caption. 1 page.
- Memorial Service signature book, April, 1999 (Box-folder 2-11)
  Memorial Service signature book. Ringed binder. Also included memorial service invitation (2 copies). Five pages of signatures.
- Appointment book, 1974 - 1975 (Box-folder 2-12)
  Dr. Radley's appointment book includes handwrittten notes, receipts (from hotels, restaurants, stores), and vouchers (loose and stapled). Black cover, spiral-bound.
- Appointment book, January, 1976 - July, 1976 (Box-folder 2-13)
  Dr. Radley's appointment book includes handwritten notes, lists, receipts (loose and stapled) and vouchers reflecting her travels, meetings, and lectures. Black cover, sprial-bound.
- Appointment book, 1976 - 1977 (Box-folder 2-14)
  Includes handwritten notes and a few loose notes and miscellaneous papers. Also included is Dr. Radley's business card while Executive Vice President - Provost. Black cover, sprial-bound.
- Appointment book, August, 1976 - April, 1977 (Box-folder 2-15)
  The appointment book is very full of handwritten notes, business receipts, vouchers, and statements reflect Dr. Radley's travels, lectures and professional life. Many loose papers. Handle with care and concern for original order. Black cover, sprial-bound.
- Appointment book, July, 1976 - June, 1977 (Box-folder 2-16)
  Appointment book contains handwritten notes, a few loose notes, official college calendar, Board of Trustees schedule of meetings, College Council schedule of meetings and miscellaneous papers relating to SUNY Oswego. Black cover, spiral-bound.
- Appointment book, 1976 - 1980 (Box-folder 2-17)
  These papers relate to the loose and stapled papers in Dr. Radley's appointment books, including 1976 European trip receipts from restaurants and hotels. Also includes 1976 correspondence, and1979 application for license in the citizens radio service. Spiral notebook has handwritten label, " Dr. V. L. Radley 1976 spring to summer log. Florence, Italy, Belgium, SUNY study programs ". Handwritten notes.
- SUNY College at Oswego: Its Second Century Unfolds, 1988 (Box-folder 2-18)
  "SUNY College at Oswego: Its Second Century Unfolds"by Dorothy Rogers. 1988. Signed bookplate from Virginia L. Radley, former president of SUCO and member of the Edward Austin Sheldon Society.
- SUNY Oswego plaque, 1948 (Box-folder 3-1)
  Plaque has the following information: " College at Oswego. State University of New York. Let Each Become All He Is Capable Of Being. 1948 1861 " The plaque is mounted to a green felt covered board and framed. Below the plaque is a brass label, " President Virginia Radley ".
- Framed portrait of Dr. Virginia Radley, n.d. (Box-folder 4-1)
  Framed portrait of Dr. Virginia Radley. Gold frame 21" x 17". Linen matt with gold trim. Linen is soiled. Black & white photograph. 14" x 10.5" The framed portrait was transferred to the college archives from University Development after being removed from Sheldon Hall.